[QIFREY] Long ago,
within this very cave,
was housed the prosperous
Cavern Nation of Romonon,
which specialized
in delicate magic craftsmanship.
The arrogant Romonons
adorned themselves
in magical golden expressions
of their artistry.
They looked down unsparingly
on nations and peoples
beyond their walls,
firmly convinced
of their own superiority.
This included the travelers
from the surface
who'd gotten word
of this flourishing nation.
To limit visitation
to those they deemed of value,
the Romonons devised
the Serpentback Road,
a path only the worthy
could walk.
And to further ensure that
those who did not measure up
to their exacting standard
would never reach their lands,
they carved a maze spell
into the cavern walls.
As the city's wealth
and beauty grew,
so too did the people's
haughtiness and exclusivity.
Until finally...
They had no one to cast
their judgmental eyes upon
but one another.
Those in whom
no merit was found
were deemed better fit
to decorate the city
as gold statues
than to remain
as worthless flesh.
And just as stagnant water
turns foul,
this isolated people
grew malaised.
They spent their scant
remaining energy
on internal squabbles.
And at last,
it's said they were crushed
under the weight
of their own beloved gold.
All that remains
are the magically
labyrinthine cave,
and the Serpentback Road
that lies within.
[all gasp softly]
Humans can be quite terrifying.
And one of the qualities
that makes us so terrifying
is how easily we fail
to recognize that.
- But Master...
- [BOTH] Mm?
Magic exists to bring people
happiness, right?
Its purpose is to help.
It's a miracle that
makes this world vibrant!
[Qifrey gasps softly]
If that is what you witches
of the future
truly believe to be so,
well then...
It must be, now mustn't it?
[both chuckle]
[QIFREY] Although...
I fear this particular magic
may bring unhappiness
with regards to our meal.
[both exclaim,
chatter indistinctly]
[COCO] All right!
The non-burned parts are edible!
Yummy!
[QIFREY] "Magic is a miracle
that makes this world vibrant."
- [indistinct chatter]
- [QIFREY] I hope that is so.
[COCO]
There's a really big bone!
[brushbuddy squeaking]
[QIFREY] Truly.
[♪ opening theme song playing]
[ALAIRA] Any thoughts
on how you'll proceed?
I'm afraid that
as your test proctor,
I am not permitted
to advise you.
THE SHADOW OF ROMONON
Even with its twists and turns,
it's still one path forward.
Easy.
[gasps]
All we have to do is fly...
[Richeh gasps softly]
[EUINI] Look out!
[AGOTT]
They're standing sideways?
Is that a spell of yours?
[EUINI] No, it's the magic
of the road.
Gravity is a bit topsy-turvy
in this cave.
The only place where you can
stand up straight
is on the back of the serpent.
And if you
should step off of it,
you'll be swallowed
into the labyrinth.
And carried back
to the entrance.
[Agott sighs]
Are you saying,
these serpent-scale
paving stones...
all have Casting Seals on them?
But it seems like some of them
aren't holding up very well.
Good eye. Yes.
I didn't realize that
my first time
and ended up falling.
Um, there is a spell
from the Basics
of Casting Primer.
I'm familiar.
[AGOTT] Water flows,
directed by gravity.
It stops when it reaches
level ground.
If the only level spots
are where the seals
remain intact,
then we may rely
upon the pooled water
to tell us where it's safe
to set our feet.
Wow! Absolutely correct!
You really live up
to the Arklaum name.
Yes. Even my second time,
I didn't realize that...
[RICHEH] The "correct" answer.
The "correct" spell.
The "correct" path.
If there's one thing
I don't want,
it's to follow someone else's
idea of what's "correct."
[RICHEH'S MASTER]
Here now, Richehlette.
[Richeh gasps]
Stop wasting your time
with these worthless spells.
This is no way to become
a proper witch, girl.
Why can't you simply obey
your master's instructions?
Such ridiculous scribbles.
Throw them out!
[RICHEH]
I don't want to.
They aren't scribbles.
They're my spells!
I don't want
to throw myself away.
I need to...
All right. Come along.
Well, I've identified
the way ahead,
but I can't get
the myrphon to follow me.
Now, look, unless you're in
the mood to take a nasty fall,
you might want to
pay more attention.
[myrphon chirps]
[Agott gasps]
No, your adorable
little mannerisms
are none of my concern!
[EUINI] Yes, they are.
Or at least, they should be.
Those vocalizations
are how myrphons communicate.
Therefore, if you want
to lead them effectively,
the correct answer
is to use an echoing spell
that mimics their cries, and...
Huh?
[RICHEH] There's no
one "correct" way with magic.
[myrphons chirping]
[RICHEH] No rules saying
what's right and what's wrong.
The myrphons.
I know you have
previous experience
taking this test,
but please stop blathering
about "correct answers".
And telling us what to do
before we try.
I just want to be myself.
I don't want to grow up
to be a witch who isn't me.
That means, I have to get
to the end of this road,
using only the power
of my own spells!
Richeh...
Sorry, but you can't.
I'm afraid the world
doesn't work that way.
You have to remember,
this is a test.
Tests have correct answers.
And we're apprentices,
children, still learning,
so we have to do this
by the book.
Otherwise,
I'm going to fail again.
So, let's do this
the correct way-- [gasps]
That's exactly the kind of talk
I hate more than anything!
Think, though!
Your spells, if they haven't
been tested, they could fail.
They'll work
if I make them work!
You're not making
- any sense at all!
- [AGOTT] You know...
The knowledge you gain
from your failures,
can lead you to success.
I happen to know someone
who learns quite well that way.
You take the test
however you want to.
It makes no difference to me.
I don't need your permission
to do that.
[Euini sighs]
[footsteps]
[water gushing]
[Euini gasps]
Is that water I hear? Strange.
[ALAIRA] Huh?
[EUINI] Every day, my master
drills it into my head...
"You can't do it."
- "It's beyond you."
- [Agott gasps softly]
[EUINI] And he's right.
I thought if I studied
how others worked, perhaps...
But it seems
I really can't do it.
Because we're in Romonon...
On a road created to prevent
the unworthy from passing.
[COCO] Hm?
Coco, what's wrong?
Um, Master Qifrey,
do you know if there are
any other witches here today
besides us?
[QIFREY] With Kukrow
having made his exit,
I don't believe so.
But why?
A moment ago,
I thought I saw
someone in a robe.
- [TETIA] Uh?
- [QIFREY] Is that so? Odd.
[wind blows]
[Coco grunts softly]
[Coco sighs]
[COCO] Of course
there's nobody there.
[TETIA] Coco!
[COCO] Sorry!
I'll be right there!
[AGOTT] The water falls
from the edge,
and winds about
in the strangest of ways.
This is a predicament.
Clearly, the Casting Seals
will have no effect
over the gap in the road.
We'll have to find
some way across.
- Richeh?
- The Casting Seals do their job
as long as we're
touching the stones.
So all we have to do
is extend the stones
to the other side.
Like this.
♪
[myrphon squeals]
Is she riding
a ribbon made of stone?
[RICHEH] There.
When you
can't do something,
try turning it into something
you can do.
[Euini gasps]
Makes sense, in a way.
[EUINI] Uh?
[myrphon grunts]
[EUINI] Wait. That's not safe!
You mustn't...
A combination of repetition
and replication magic.
Rather narrow path,
but it did the trick!
[Agott yelps]
- Agott!
- [AGOTT] I'm fine!
[Agott grunts]
[Agott sighs]
[AGOTT] It's difficult to draw
clean lines under my cloak,
so the spell faded more quickly
than I was expecting.
I still have a ways to go.
I have to work even harder!
Nicely done. I'm impressed.
[RICHEH] It was pretty easy.
It's your turn now.
- [Euini grunts]
- [ALAIRA] Uh?
[Euini breathing shakily]
[EUINI] I...
- I can't.
- [BOTH] Huh?
I can't do it!
[all gasp]
[EUINI] I don't have
what it takes!
The talent, courage, confidence,
aptitude, skill.
I don't have any of that!
With the road broken,
I don't even have
luck on my side!
- I'm going to fail again!
- [AGOTT] Come on!
You've already demonstrated
encyclopedic knowledge
and you have a gift
for analysis!
Not to mention the experience
of taking this test twice!
Use it!
Just try drawing a spell!
Anything!
[Euini sniffles]
[myrphon whines]
[myrphon screeches]
The myrphon cry spell?
[BOTH] Uh?
[AGOTT] And a rain spell
to make puddles.
Why are you casting spells
that address problems
we've solved already?
If you want to get across,
you need something new!
[Euini breathes uneasily]
I... I can't draw.
Why?
[EUINI] Because... I can't make
my hands stop shaking.
[EUINI] This always happens
when someone else is watching.
It makes it impossible
for me to draw properly.
I feel their eyes on me.
I start to sweat and tremble.
I ruin the lines.
And the spells
turn out terribly.
I wish there was something
I could do.
But I feel so helpless.
And the more people witness
my pathetic panicking,
the worse
that panicking becomes.
It's a vicious circle.
I really thought
I could make it this time.
I prepared, I studied.
I looked up
all the "correct answer" spells.
And drew them in advance.
When I'm alone,
I can concentrate
and have no trouble drawing.
And there's no rule
against bringing
our Palm Quires with us.
I'd only need to close
the circles to cast the spells.
It would look as though
I was doing everything right.
And then... came a gap
in the road...
My punishment for violating
the spirit of the test.
Why must I be like this
all the time?
You said you just wanted
to be yourself.
But me? [cries]
I just want to stop being me.
I wish I could be
anyone else!
[Euini cries]
[AGOTT] This test
hinges on one's ability
to cast spells in front
of Outsiders unnoticed.
It's unfortunate.
But at this rate,
he'll never be able to pass.
- You can do it.
- [Agott gasps]
[RICHEH] I know you can
do this just as you are.
You told us it's possible.
Isn't it obvious?
If you need to be alone to draw,
then be alone, right now!
Be alone?
[Euini sniffles]
[EUINI] But... but how?
[RICHEH] However you can!
Magic can make stones grow,
or cause drops of rain
to start falling
from out of nowhere.
So figure out a way to be alone!
[EUINI] I... I can't draw
a spell like that.
[RICHEH]
Don't use a spell, then!
What? But that's absurd!
I can't come up with some
miracle solution on the spot!
[Euini continues crying]
- [myrphon grunts]
- [ALAIRA] Mm?
What are you...
Leave him be.
[Euini continues crying]
[EUINI]
I hate this so much!
It's the worst!
I must look ridiculous.
This is the only idea
I was able to come up with.
It's so pathetic,
I could cry!
Everyone must be disgusted
with me right now.
Unless they're laughing,
at what an outlandish spectacle
I'm making of myself.
In a way, I'm almost grateful
I can't get a glimpse
of how stupid I look.
And the proctor...
she has to be disappointed.
[Euini gasps softly]
[EUINI] They're not laughing.
No one's disgusted,
or laughing, or judging me.
No one but me.
Turn it into something
you can do.
I see.
All this time, the curse
that's been sabotaging me
was the work of my own
twisted reflection.
Reflection.
[Euini gasps]
Right here.
No, here?
The Casting Seal
in the Mirror Cloak.
It's not a mirror.
It's signs of reflection
and concealment.
It conceals the wearer's form
within shadow,
then projects
the image of a beast
reflected in its scales.
Truly incredible.
This is quite the layered spell.
Oh, wait!
So then, perhaps I...
[Euini breathes uneasily, sighs]
[exhales deeply]
What's the matter? [gasps]
Euini!
Stay back!
I'll erect a wind barrier!
A Romonon trap...
Or some ancient, unknown spell!
[EUINI] No, it's all right.
Don't worry. This is my spell!
Euini!
♪
Oh, my!
Euini, what have you done
to your cloak?
Well, uh, when I was hiding,
I found the, uh...
the Casting Seal.
Then I erased the "mirror" part,
and turned it into
a "cloak of borrowshade."
Now I can hide in the dark,
and draw whenever I need to.
The myrphon
can't see me anymore,
so it might be a bit harder
to bring it along.
But I can still mimic
its cries with my spell!
What's important is,
it can't tell I'm human, right?
[ALAIRA] Well, technically.
Being hidden
is just like being alone.
If I can't be seen,
I'll be able to concentrate!
Yes! I do believe
I'll be able to draw!
[myrphon screeching]
[Alaira gasps]
[Euini exclaims, chuckles]
[EUINI] A slightly
embarrassing way to do it,
but you know?
I think this might be me.
And you're all right with that?
Being you?
Yes. Well, somewhat.
[Richeh chuckles softly]
In that case, from now on,
stop saying
you can't do something
before you've even attempted it.
I will try not to,
and if I do, then I will try
not to leave it at that.
Oh, hold on!
Richeh, thank you!
And here I thought you had
no interest in helping others.
He's the one who started it
by saving me
at the cave entrance,
so now we're even.
Besides...
not being able
to do something you want...
I know that feeling.
Well, of course you do.
That feeling is natural.
It's what lets us improve.
I'm going to become
a better version of myself.
I refuse to tolerate
an inferior version
under any circumstances.
[ALAIRA] The purpose of tests
is to learn about yourself.
Even on "one path forward,"
there are any number of spells
one might cast.
We search for our
very own way,
and use it to walk
our very own path.
All by facing
challenges like these.
See? Tests aren't so bad,
now are they?
[RICHEH] Huh?
Hmm.
- [Alaira chuckles, gasps]
- [RICHEH] Still...
I'm going to stay mad
at Master Qifrey
for lying and making me take it
until he tells me he's sorry.
He gets one Angricheh point.
- [ALAIRA] Angricheh point?
- [myrphon chirps] Uh?
Ah, yes, that's right,
on the subject
of Master Qifrey...
- [RICHEH] Huh?
- I was wondering
if you've recently
heard him mention a...
[gasping]
[Alaira yelps]
[BOTH] Miss Alaira!
[ALAIRA] The Brimmed Caps!
[Alaira grunts]
[AGOTT] This is bad!
Listen to me!
The Brimmed Caps
cannot be trusted!
Don't be misled!
Run, as fast as you...
Forbidden magic is...
[AGOTT] Miss Alaira?
[♪ closing theme song playing]
EPISODE 13:
FORBIDDEN MAGIC